Three...
I've been studyin' real seriously...
Nobody understands that.
You've got exams this year.
Try a little harder.
Run a little longer!
You need to sing a little louder.
That's what I'm doin'!
Chin up, Hiroshi.
Don't just barge in!
Nothin' wrong with gettin' all threes.
Yer pa got all threes, too!
That's right!
Yer already on the track to mediocrity!
Bein' mediocre just makes ya unique, right?
If ya don't need somethin', get out!
We do need you to do somethin'.
Here.
Take this champon to Sensei.
Y'know, shouldn't you reconsider this?
Ain't no need for you to
be cookin' for a stranger.
I'm gonna tell him, "Cook your own food."
You don't understand nothin'!
Don't you realize how doin' things for
Sensei gives your mother purpose?
With a son who can care for himself,
and a lethargic husband who just says
"s'good" no matter what I feed him...
In a life with no challenges,
only Sensei's existence revives my
heart as a mother, and as a woman...
Barakamon
Yakamashika
Translation:
Annoying
It's been a week since I came to this island.
I still haven't written anything I'm satisfied with...
That was just spur of the moment.
FUN
I can't call it my own style.
I came here to immerse myself in writing,
and to triumph over that man...
Focus...
Sensei!
You again? Why do you come here every day?
'Cuz I'm yer commuter wife!
Where did you learn that?
Hello!
It's Miwa-nee and Tama!
Ooh! So this's the guy!
I've never seen someone in a
stylish jinbei like that before.
Ain't been to the base in a while.
Hey! Don't come in without permission!
Augh! The posters're all torn down!
The CDs are gone, too.
Hey!
What are you doing, barging in here?
Yer the one who barged in!
This was our base!
Anyway, where's our stuff?
Don't tell me you pitched it!
The stuff that was in here when
I moved in is all inside in that box.
Oh, good!
These're important to us, y'know.
Look, this isn't your base anymore.
Hey!
What are you putting up?!
We ain't got no mind to leave here.
Well, leave! Someone lives here now!
Don't be so uptight!
You know yer happy to be mixin' with young girls.
Don't say stuff that's easily misunderstood!
It was you, wasn't it?!
You taught this child all those indecent words!
That lady's the queen of Kabuki-cho!
Since it's nice out, I'll go streetwalking!
This miso soup is labial!
You should be more careful from now on.
Tellin' us that won't do any good.
Yeah!
Ya just memorized stuff ya
overheard us sayin', right?
Yep, no one taught me nothin'.
You be careful too, Sensei.
Kids her age parrot phrases like a myna bird.
I'm saying, the language you use is—
"Esu Emu"?
Wait, Naru!
I wrote that for work.
Meanin' it's for an S&M Club, right?
No, it's not!
Esu Emu!
Esu Emu! Esu Emu!
Esunic (Ethnic) Restaurant
Emupamuuza
This is for a restaurant signboard!
What're you makin', Tama?
Hey! Don't use my calligraphy
tools without permission!
All done!
Ta-da!
Loser
Write something nicer!
Yer real good, Tama!
Yeah, really!
I can tell you're aimin' to write manga.
Don't talk about me wantin' to write manga!
You may be better'n Sensei!
Hey, yeah!
Maybe it's actually easy to become a calligrapher!
Don't underestimate me, brats!
LOSER
Look! This is real calligraphy!
Amazin'!
Don't quite get why, though.
Yeah, I don't really get it, either.
There's a penmanship assignment
in our summer homework.
Let's have Sensei look at it.
Nice idea!
If I learn from Sensei, a big
prize won't be just a dream.
So, please help us out, Sensei!
All right! Leave it to me!
Okay! We'll come back tomorrow!
Bye-bye!
!
What have I done?!
And those feelings
excite your mother as a woman...
Ah, I get it already! I'm goin'!
Focus...
Sensei!
I brought Hina this time!
You know,
I don't have time to play right now!
Go play outside!
Focus, focus...
If I ignore them, they'll leave eventually...
Mosquito.
There!
Hey! Hold it!
I forgot somethin'...
This's fun!
S&M...
No, it's not!
Don't come back today, any of you!
Poo.
This is bad... I feel dizzy...
Sheesh...
We're stuck dealin' with some guy
too old to be this high-maintenance.
A calligrapher's gotta be a real snobby jerk.
I hafta make it clear we
can't go on feedin' him.
Hey! I know you're there!
Come out already!
Listen, jerk! Answer when someone's calli—
Hey...
I'm back!
Hiroshi! What're you doin' to Sensei?!
I ain't doin' nothin'!
What do I do?
Just take the champon!
All right!
Everyone! Lend me your energy!
I said take the champon!
Good thing it's wrapped.
Yeah...
Don't look so great, though.
Still, why's he on the verge of death?
He's always like that this time of day.
He's been writin' stuff for
a calligraphy contest.
Up all night, huh?
I get like that before tests, too.
Well, between me and a guy with talent,
I guess all-nighters don't mean the same.
Hiroshi, what's "talent"?
It's when a guy can do anything
with just a little effort,
when a guy like me can't do nothin'
no matter how hard he tries.
Did you get all threes even though ya tried hard?
Hey, who'd you hear that from?!
Woohoo!
I feel like workin' hard, too!
Who told you that?!
By golly!
Ain't nobody who can beat me at that!
Hey!
Listen to me!
It's hidden in this room.
Hey, now...
Just bargin' into a room is—
What's with this room?
I'm pretty sure it's in that box.
Hold it, Naru!
You see, Sensei
says he still can't write nothin' good
even after writin' all this.
Because Sensei ain't got talent,
even after writin' lots,
he thinks it's not enough.
UTMOST
I think Sensei's amazin', but I
don't much understand "talent."
I've studied this much already. That's enough.
You dyed your hair?
Yeah. I'm goin' with this style from now on.
You sure do everything half-assed.
I do everything half-assed...
So that's why I get all threes...
Hiroshi?
Naru, on second thought,
Sensei really does have talent.
What?
You can tell, Hiroshi?
No, I don't actually get it.
What?
You were fakin'?!
Being able to work hard
is the best talent of all.
Oh! Hiroshi, you cryin'?
No, I'm not!
Liar! Yer definitely cryin'!
And yer a grown-up!
Shut up! Don't look at me!
What was that?!
Ta-da!
Cicada shells!
Why?
It's my talent.
Nobody can beat me at collectin' these.
That's talent, right?
Well...
If you try with all your might
so nobody can beat you,
that might be talent.
Oh, so you're the Village Chief's son.
Sorry to have you all do so much for me.
Uh...
This is the last time we can bring you food.
Ma won't say it, but I think
you've gotten to be a burden.
I've been a burden?
Besides, I plan to study seriously
for my exams from now on.
I'd like to try following your example,
and make a proper effort.
I really like your mom's meat and potato
stew, but I guess it can't be helped.
Have you been listening to me?
Okay.
I'll bring you some homemade
meat and potato stew for dinner.
No, that's not what I meant...
I'd feel bad if that messy champon
was your last meal from us.
Later!
I have to start cooking for myself tomorrow?
Sensei, you gonna make rice or somethin'?
Maybe I'll make curry.
Yeah!
Sensei!
I came to play again—
Am-ambulance!
Nanatsutake Hospital
Handa Sei
Private Room
Heatstroke, sleep deprivation, poor appetite...
I'm admitting you for one night.
Okay...
For goodness' sake, Sensei, why didn't
you say you weren't feelin' well?
I'm sorry.
I kind of ended up with insomnia.
Sensei, will you get better?
Yeah, I'm hooked up to an IV, so I'll be fine.
Huh...
Does it hurt worse'n a shot?
I'm not sure...
Well, Sensei.
We'll fetch what you need
for stayin' the night here.
Uh, right.
If you need anything,
feel free to call on Iku-chan.
This here nurse may be young,
but she's a married woman.
Don't go puttin' hands on her.
Like I'd want to do that.
Sensei...
Did you know shots hurt worse than IVs?
Now I've done it.
I guess I've been pretty tense.
I have to get back to writing soon.
And what are you still doing here?
Vroom!
Put down the toy car and listen!
Oh, here it is!
'Scuse us!
You all right, Sensei?
We came to wish you well.
You girls came all this way to see me?
It's a school day, see.
Our middle school's near here.
Oh, so I'm just a side trip.
That's still nice though, ain't it?
Sensei, your IV's about to run out!
What?!
Won't it just refill itself
once the bag runs out?
It's nothin' that high-tech!
Naru! Use the nurse-call!
Nasu (eggplant)?
There ain't no nasu here!
Nasu! Nasu! Nasu, nasu, nasu!
If you don't call Iku-neechan soon,
air will get into Sensei's arm and he'll die!
Handa Sei
Private Room
But there's no nasu!
The button's right by his pillow!
Pillow-talk! Pillow-talk!
Ack, Sensei fainted!
He's spineless!
There was no need to panic.
The recent models won't let air get in.
Oh, yeah? I had no idea!
Give me a break!
I was already in bad shape.
Sensei, your temperature has gone up a little.
Shall I insert a suppository to lower it?
Suppository?!
Why're you reacting, too?
No!
I refuse to engage in humiliation-play!
Humiliation-play?
This is standard medical care.
When that was done to
me back in grade school,
I got so embarrassed that I threw up...
You don't need to confess your trauma to me.
We'll keep him under observation for now.
Girls, don't go gettin' him overexcited.
Okay!
Huh?
Where's Naru?
What're you doin' down here?
Come out of there.
You'll dirty your clothes.
No!
I'll be sure to press it next time.
If anything happens to Sensei,
I'll press the nasu!
Look, the IV's all full now.
Nothing's gonna happen for a while!
But...
There's a ghost here...
A ghost?
Grampa told me
that there's a ghost in this hospital.
It's scarier'n a monster.
Nobody knows what it is.
Truth is, I'm scared, but...
I wanna see it just once!
Her grampa totally made that up.
What're you doin'?
I'm not listening to you guys.
I don't believe in ghosts.
What'll you do if I hear you talking about
scary stuff and can't sleep tonight?
This hospital is old, so it's really scary!
How 'bout a suppository?
Why'd you flinch?
'Sup?
I brought the stuff you asked for.
And my writing tools?
No way.
Why not?!
I've been waiting for those!
You just collapsed from overwork!
You need to rest!
I'm most relaxed when I'm working!
Are you stupid? I'm worried about you!
Your eyes are goin' wild!
What did you say?!
What's the matter?!
Okay, time for us to be headin' home.
Later!
Bye-bye!
Guess I'll go back...
Hello there.
Oh, uh, hello there.
Did I startle you?
Just a little.
I'm in the room next to yours.
Sounded mighty lively in there earlier.
I'm very sorry. Did we bother you?
Oh, no, no.
So, what's ailin' you?
Nothing that bad, really.
Just a summer cold.
Can't be "just a cold."
Weren't they all worried about you?
Those kids seemed mighty relieved
when they heard you were safe.
Please get to feelin' better soon.
HEARTBEAT
Handa-san?!
What are you doing?!
Please tell the Village Chief
to bring me my writing tools!
Your fever hasn't gone down yet!
It's now or never!
I have to write while the idea's still fresh!
I'm begging you!
Please let me write!
Come on!
No!
I have to write it now!
Stop, Sensei!
One moment is everything!
No! You can't, Sensei!
I have a husband!
Sorry 'bout this.
I thought you should know.
His fever's gone up from excitement,
so I'll give him a suppository for sleepin'.
Sensei!
You all better now?
Yeah. See for yourself.
Ooh, thank goodness!
Your color does look a lot better.
It's thanks to the sposi-tree!
I'll fill your prescriptions.
Be sure to take them as directed.
Why are you so far away?
Don't test my love for my husband!
Like I said, why?!
Now to hurry back so I can write!
Oh, you're raring to go, eh?
The old man in the room next to mine
really cheered me up yesterday.
He's in this room... Hm?
Uh, where's the old man who was in this room?
Old man?
You were the only patient here yesterday.
Most folks just go to the new facility.
Huh...
Sensei, did ya see a ghost?
Sensei!
Hello?
I brought meat and potato stew!
What'd you do to your hands?!
Uh, it's nothing!
Nothing at all!
Sensei!
What do I do with these
blood-soaked onions you cut?
That's not blood!
It's a spice! Like Tabasco!
That's what the red stuff is!
Ma, I get the feeling I understand
what you were talking about now.
We'll continue to bring
you food from now on.
Huh?! Are you sure?!
Ain't that great, Sensei?