It's no good if yer always lookin' up.
Wait patiently...
And take it once it hits the ground.
It's no good to always be looking up.
Move patiently... at my own pace.
If I practice calligraphy steadily,
without cutting corners on my work,
then, in time, I may find my own style.
Still...
Movie: Demon Aher 2
What kind of movie is this?
Te~pid Tea
Myopic Detective: Hot Springs Arc
Movie: Demon Aher 2
OR Health Comes First
Extra:
250 Life Lessons Learned from Pandas
It was popular enough to get a sequel?
Okay.
Huh?
It's broken!
What'll I do now?!
I doubt this island has a place
that will fix computers.
Oh! Kawafuji!
!
It hasn't worked right since
I dropped it in the ocean...
It's finally busted completely?
No computer, no cell phone, no landline...
How can I contact anyone
from a place like this?!
Barakamon
Shiman Ontsandon
Translation:
Island Dads
A whole month has passed
since I came to this island.
Contrary to the slow life I expected,
my days are unexpectedly busy.
Amidst all that,
there is one place that always heals my heart.
There you are!
Yes...
This place is a paradise for cat lovers.
So cute...
I want to pet them...
But this is someone else's property.
C'mon, come closer!
Shoo! Shoo! You filchin' felines!
things broke into the fridge again!
Landsakes, no need to get so mad.
Anyone'd be mad, if their
sashimi dinner got eaten up!
Oh, Sensei, you need somethin'?
Ah, so you like cats, too.
Well, come see 'em anytime you like.
What?! Can I really?
They're all strays that settled
here before I realized.
Th-Then, I won't hold back.
Here, kitties!
I told ya, they're strays.
They don't come near people.
Please say so sooner.
What am I supposed to do with my arms now?
We could tempt 'em with this.
Stew left over from lunch.
C'mere, Whitey!
Wow, a bunch came over!
With the sashimi gone,
those "leftovers from lunch"
should be my dinner...
Wow, a bunch came over!
So you named one "Whitey"?
I just call 'em that when I call 'em.
They're just strays.
Society would consider these pet cats, though.
What about that tabby cat?
C'mere, Blackie!
Not "Tabby"?
Blackie's the one that's closest to people.
The other strays won't let you pet 'em,
but Blackie's a smart cookie.
*Smart Cookie = Good Kitty
Wanna hold one, Sensei?
Can I really?
I do! Please let me hold one!
All right...
Hurry up an' take it! I can't hold it long!
I don't know how!
Make a bold grab!
Then hold on tight with both hands!
All right!
I got it!
Nothing to it.
Even a stray kitten is still cute.
I told ya to hold on tight!
Say, are you all right?
Sensei, you got a rash on yer neck!
What is this?
It itches!
My eyes itch, too!
Sensei, think ya might be allergic to cats?
Allergic to cats?
Oh, a cat!
Don't, Sei.
You shouldn't approach animals carelessly.
You don't want to be itchy, do you?
If that happens, I can't take the itching from you.
So I can never have a cat...
I never would've known if I hadn't touched one.
Excuse me!
Shopkeeper, the phone—
It's Sensei!
What'd you come for?
For shoppin'?
You kids are everywhere...
Oh, Sensei, you got a rash on your neck.
Don't remind me...
Where's the shopkeeper?
She went to the senior center.
You may shop if you like.
No, I just need to borrow the phone.
Sensei, d'ya know Akki?
Akki?
Yeah, Akki!
I am Akki.
Akki's amazin'!
He's real good at video games!
He's like Master Takahashi!
Who's Takahashi?
Play For Just One Hour Each Day
Ya don't know Master Takahashi?
Huh?! Is he really that famous?!
16 Hits
Is he a kyogen performer or something?
He's a master at video games.
You need the telephone, right?
Yeah.
Akki, huh...
I feel like I've seen him somewhere before...
Are you Tama's younger brother?!
Well... yes, I am...
Wow, you look so much like her!
Are you a clone?!
Please stop. We don't look alike.
No, you do!
Genetics are amazing!
Please, just hurry up and use the phone!
It bothers you that much?
Here!
Woah, it's black!
Yes, because it's a black telephone.
What is this thing?
I've only seen these on television.
In an era of cell phones with cameras and
touch-sensitive screens, why is this here?
I scared ya!
I'll be playing a game,
so help yourself to the phone.
Uh, sure.
I'm about to make an important
phone call, so be quiet.
Let's see...
Zero...
What the heck?
Nothing happens when I press it.
Is this thing broken?
Um...
You don't press on it.
You turn it.
I knew that!
This black phone is just
stiff and hard to turn!
He blamed the phone...
Like this, right?
See? I turned it!
Indeed, you did.
You can take yer finger out now.
I knew that!
It won't work unless you pick
up the receiver before dialing.
Just tell me the number you want to call.
I'll dial it for you.
If you pity me, give me money!
Yes, hello...
Be quiet, I'm on the phone!
Oh, Kawafuji?
Sounds lively on your end.
What do you need?
My computer broke, so I need to get a new one.
I can't get work without it.
About that, Handa.
I'd like you to take a break
from work for a while.
Huh? What do you mean?
Autumn's the deadline for the
Naruka Institute Exhibition.
This is no time for you to be working.
As your friend, I thought I should look out for you.
What's the date?
September 10th.
41st Naruka Institute Calligraphy Exhibition
Naruka
Sept. 10
Handa &
Kanzaki
Well, we can let it go this time
if you don't feel up to it,
but if you consider...
Order the writing equipment
I'm about to describe.
Can I expect you to get the grand prize this time?
I'm not sure.
Right now I'm in total darkness,
but I'll definitely find the light, someday.
Definitely.
So, what's the cost per minute?
"Right now I'm in total darkness..."
"But I'll definitely find the light."
Was what I said that bad?
In eighth grade, you claimed to harbor
some power in your left arm, didn't you?
That's beside the point!
I talked for about five minutes,
so will fifty yen be enough?
The phone costs ten yen per call.
Is that really enough?
Gramma says to use it for free,
but everyone leaves ten yen.
Okay, here's ten yen.
And this comes to forty yen.
Naru!
Yay!
And Hina!
Sorry about that.
Here, you too, Akki.
Thank you very much.
Look!
I made a nice, fat balloon!
Hey! Don't touch it with your dirty hand!
Hina!
What the heck did you do?!
I'd assumed that a calligrapher
would be more stuffy.
I never would've known the
truth if I hadn't met you.
You're an odd person, like they say.
Odd?
Can I come to visit sometime?
You mean I'll have both siblings
coming to trash my house?
C'mon over!
Don't answer for me!
...
None of this is good enough!
Can't write anything...
Maybe it's because I stopped working
to focus on the exhibition.
Writing even a single sheet
feels like a huge undertaking.
If I can't improve my mood and
write something, the deadline—
Hey! What're you tryin' to do?!
Ya spilled all the seaweed
I worked hard to collect!
Sorry! I was lost in thought...
Lost in thought?
Ya expect to get off the hook
with an excuse like that?
Ya think that's enough?!
He's a gangster!
Ain't seen your face before...
I moved in recently—
Yer the penmanship teacher?!
Y-Yes, I am.
I heard yer an odd person, but a bad apple?!
Odd again...
Yer gonna do me a little favor, Sensei...
Hey, wait! Where are we going?!
Don't worry about it!
Oh, forgot my bike.
Caught by a Grade-A annoying old guy!
Okay, Sensei!
Do yer thing.
Write on it, real flashy!
Yer outta luck, gettin' caught up with my dad.
After I told him 'bout you,
he exclaimed, "I'll have
him write my boat's name!"
He's your dad?
I give up on everything.
I can't wait...
He looks like he'd never forgive any failure.
Dad is mighty scary when he's mad.
Will the boat's name be
"Miwa-maru," as the custom goes?
Dad's a liquor seller.
He just bought the boat for fun.
I ain't gonna give it my name.
Small Craft Registration Form
Boat Name: Yuigadokuson-Maru
(I Alone Am Holy)
Owner: Yamamura Iwao
Very unique taste...
I'm so glad Mom picked my name.
What's "Yuigadokuson" mean?
It means that I'm God, of course!
I'm so embarrassed...
They're definitely related...
Five kanji characters...
That's a lot.
And with the curves of the hull,
it'll be hard to keep them balanced.
These aren't my usual tools, either.
Even discounting the pressure
he's putting on me,
I definitely can't afford to mess this up!
It's paint!
Ta-da!
Bam!
The paint's gonna melt yer hands.
Wash it off!
I need to make a draft,
so I'll go write it at home and come back.
Wha?!
Yuigadokuson-Maru
First, I'll cut out the letters that I wrote,
then I'll paint over the stencil...
Now hold on, Sensei!
That's like all those other cookie-cutter boats!
I want my boat to be one-of-a-kind!
Sure, but these aren't my usual writing tools,
and it's on something other than paper.
If you want it done right,
you should ask a specialist...
What, yer tellin' me to head out t'sea
in some ugly mass-produced boat?!
No, I'm not!
But if I mess up, it'll be ugly anyway.
So, yer gonna mess up, Sensei?
No, I won't!
But I can't rule anything out...
Ain't nothin' to worry 'bout.
Now, get writin'!
But I told you...
Can a pro really be turnin' down work?
I'll decide what's ugly!
If I wanted to sail this out
with print-out writin' on it,
I'd have Naru do the job!
Now that's—
Okay, that's enough!
I've... sailed in to the rescue! Get it?
Dad, it's time for yer liquor deliveries.
Sensei, just whip somethin' up!
What're you sayin'?!
"Whip something up"?!
What d'you mean, "whip something up"?!
Like you always do!
C'mon! A liquor seller's gotta sell liquor!
What do you mean, "like I always do"?!
That  gangster dad's got me cornered!
Still, I'm not one to back away from
anything after being talked to like that!
I'll have him thanking me in tears!
That said, I really need to get
used to this kind of brush.
Sensei!
The paint won't come off!
Our hands'll melt!
Nah.
Relax, it won't melt your hands.
More importantly, is there anything
I can use for test writing?
Sensei!
There's lots of boards up here!
This is more than enough for test writing.
Thanks a lot.
Uh...
Yay!
What were their names, again?
It's easier than I expected.
I wanna write, too!
This is work.
Wait up!
Jacker Cyclone!
I'm mostly used to this brush now.
Summer Belly-Band Undersea Franken
My inner voice is really revealing itself, though...
Gangster Dad                                      Demon
Somehow, I have a feeling
I can write decent calligraphy.
Yuigadokuson-Maru (ha!) Gangster
Demon Aher    Phantom Gangster
Here I go!
Huh? Wait, I forgot to consider
the curvature of the hull!
Crap! At this rate...
I'll mess up!
That was close!
But now my neck hurts!
I'm glad, but my neck hurts!
I forgot to examine the hull!
I nearly messed up, !
All right, this area looks good...
Don't push it!
We ain't doin' nothin'.
it, why?!
I did all that test writing!
Faced with this pure white boat,
I'm too scared to move the brush.
Won't I mess it up?
Oh, man... oh, man...
You okay, Sensei?
Ya better hurry before Miwa-nee gets back!
Shut up!
You're distracting me! Go away!
I hate this!
I'm scared... I'm scared... I'm scared...
He said he hates it.
Yeah.
Calm down, calm down!
I've been under pressure before.
It took a while before I
could write something good,
but I still pulled through when I had to.
I'll do it just like then...
I'm first!
All right! I'll do it, too!
Me, too!
And me!
What are you doing, you brats?!
What have you done?!
Now it's a mess!
Well, you were sayin' you hated it.
That's not what I meant!
I have to cover up the handprints.
It splattered me!
Deal with it! I got splashed, too!
I need to use strokes this bold
to cover up the handprints!
Naru! Put ink in the bowl!
Ayup!
Hina, stay back so your
clothes don't get dirty!
Aww...
Kenta, put paper beneath wherever
the ink's about to drip!
Ayup!
It's strange.
I was so scared just a moment ago,
but the pressure's completely gone,
and the brush is moving easily.
Just because of these little handprints...
Hurry up! I'm running out!
Ayup!
He's havin' a lot of fun, huh?
He's always like that.
Village Chief said he's a guy
who laughs while workin',
an' it looks to be true.
Here, take this seaweed as thanks.
All this?
Wait, isn't this the seaweed I just picked up?
How do I eat this?
Well, you did a great job.
I'll call when it's launchin' time,
so you better come see!
I didn't expect you to be this happy with it.
I'm mighty glad I asked you, Sensei.
It's more my boat than I ever imagined!
Good for you.
Over there's my hand—
It was difficult to write calligraphy on a boat,
so it was good experience.
Once I thought of it as soiling white paper,
that made it easy to do.
Thank you ever so much...
for entrusting this to me!
Nah, I thank you.
Well, setting that aside...
You've amassed quite a lot of
resentment toward me, haven't ya?
What brought this on?!
Summer Belly-Band Undersea Franken
Gangster Dad                                          Demon
Yuigadokuson-Maru (ha!) Gangster
Demon Aher    Phantom Gangster
Er, those were...
No worries, Sensei!
Those boards're meant for ferrying passengers.
What're you gonna do 'bout this?!
I...
I'm very sorry!
He ran away! Some adult!
Plus, he dropped his seaweed!
Sensei, yer seaweed!
Yer seaweed!
Sensei!
There's a lot of trash around here.
Yeah, guys who come to fish
here just toss stuff away.
They don't heed warnings, either.
Why don't you try putting up
a well-phrased billboard?
"Because of your littering,
the world is coming to an end."
Too large-scale. It doesn't feel realistic.
"Don't toss out trash, you're trash."
That'll rub them the wrong way.
"Litter and you'll die."
Not enough.
Fine, you think of one!
"Litter here, and you'll fester
where the sun doesn't shine."
A dirty joke?!
If you litter, all the crayfish will go away.