It was difficult to write calligraphy on a boat,
so it was a good experience.
Once I thought of it as soiling white paper,
that made it easy to do.
Thanks to that, my brush feels less heavy now.
There's one month until the Naruka
Institute Calligraphy Exhibition.
With a month, this time I should be...
Here! Eat up!
What is this?
Konomon.
Konomon?
All of this for me?
I'll come bringin' more when you run out.
He really does come and
go through the back way.
There's no way I can eat all
this pickled daikon myself.
It's good!
However, I need to focus on calligraphy now.
I'll use a more novel calligraphy style,
for an artistic konomon—
Not "konomon"!
I'll write!
I'll write on konomon—
Not "konomon"!
The Konomon Institute Calligraphy
Exhibition is next month—
Not "Konomon" Institute Calligraphy Exhibition!
Konomon!
Konomon.
Konomon
Konomon!
Barakamon
Un ni Oegii
Translation: Going Swimming at the Beach
Konomon... konomon...
Konomon?
I'll come bringin' more when you run out.
Konomon!
Teach us calligraphy!
It's you guys?!
That's awful rude of you.
Sorry.
Here.
Grampa said ya can never have
too much, an' told me to bring this.
Thank you...
Sensei, help us with our assignment.
First, hold the brush in your right hand.
This's my right hand!
Exactly.
You can't do calligraphy left-handed?
It's not impossible, but inkstone
placement and such make it harder.
So, what's your assignment?
Let's see...
Learning From The Past
It's this.
Okay, I'll write the example, so watch closely.
That's too close.
You ain't writin' all fuzzy like usual?
Learning From
The Past
"Fuzzy"...?
Everything begins with the fundamentals.
I wanna do writin' like that.
It's real showy!
MU
(Nil)
Ah, I'm still perfecting that.
Once it's done and acknowledged,
then I'll instruct you in it.
Acknowledged? By whom?
Until I win grand prize at the Naruka Institute
Calligraphy Exhibition next month.
Even if it don't win a prize,
it looks plenty good to me.
Instead of fussin' over that stuff,
I'd rather have fun writin'.
Have fun, huh...
You three really are kids.
Here, you'll write this, Naru.
Yay! "Cat"!
All right!
Now that I'm your teacher,
you'll definitely win prizes.
Once you do, you're sure to understand why
I care so much about winning them.
You'll write for one full hour, starting now!
Focus.
You can't apply ink twice.
That stroke shouldn't trail off.
It should stop short.
Don't sleep!
Man, I'm pooped!
Hey, all of you! No slacking off!
You're the ones who asked for my help.
I won't let you get less than grand prize.
But how many times are ya gonna make
us write the same thing over and over?
Isn't there a trick to writing well?
You're naïve!
Do you really think it's simple for
professionals to write beautifully?!
You need to understand the passion that
goes into a single sheet of calligraphy.
Thousands, millions, of predecessors
have committed trillions, quadrillions,
of thoughts to paper!
Like who?
Beats me.
Despite physical fatigue and mental breakdown...
You face the solitude single-mindedly!
Yes, the utmost limit.
You see the utmost limit!
Utmost limit...
With each step...
With each step, you get closer to perfection.
Yet an endless desert still stretches before you.
You can walk no further.
You're tired of writing.
The moment you think that,
you see it...
The God of Calligraphy!
However, even that god is just
another mirage in the desert!
Never seen anyone hallucinate
over calligraphy before.
Thing is,
we don't wanna go that far just
for a middle school assignment!
Go buy us some drinks!
I knew you guys had no motivation—
No, we do!
We do, so let us rest already!
Sheesh!
Be sure you keep practicing until I return!
All right, all right!
Sensei's an honest-to-goodness calligraphy nut.
Yah!
Ain't no way he can get a girlfriend like that.
I don't know...
He could have a long-distance relationship.
Girlfriend?!
Maybe I'll snoop around the room for evidence...
Cut it out. That's rude.
Kawafuji-san?
Could be his girlfriend!
Ah! Miwa-chan, don't just...
Oh, it's a man.
What? Let me see!
Why're you so interested?
A commemorative photo?
Maybe he's datin' one of 'em.
How 'bout her?
She's pretty, but she's standing kinda far from him.
Maybe this one?
Ain't she too plain to be Sensei's girlfriend?
Why would her looks matter?
As long as she can talk about
calligraphy, that's enough.
Ya really think there's a woman
who'd listen to his delusions?
By golly!
If it's just listening,
even a monkey could do it.
Here!
What's wrong, Naru?
Sensei said this's his treasure.
What is it?
A picture frame?
I bet there's a picture of his sweetheart in it!
What's wrong?
I just can't believe Sensei's a married woman!
Naru, that's not how you use that phrase.
Naru sure does love Sensei a lot.
C'mon, don't worry.
At his age, it'd be weirder
if he'd never dated a woman.
In another ten years,
you'll be the beauty, Naru.
You can appropriate him then.
"Up-rope-ree-ate"?
Now, let's take a look!
At Sensei's girlfriend!
Su
Shi
I bought your drinks.
Hey, what are you girls doing?!
If you don't straighten up, you won't
win anything, much less grand prize!
You're already 23 years old, Sensei!
Look at other things besides calligraphy!
What're you thinkin', gettin'
turned on by historical figures?!
Come back to reality!
Sensei, you should go out with Naru.
By golly!
Me, me! I'll up-rope-ree-ate you!
Appropriate?
Uh, hey!
Sto—
Yer gonna die alone at this rate!
What do you mean?!
Up-rope-ree-ate!
And what are you talking about?!
An ocean swim?
The kids are going on a trip to the beach,
and I'd like you to chaperone.
I asked their teacher first, but...
I'm goin' fishin'!
Oh...
They all can swim, right?
If I just have to watch them, that's fine.
Well, actually...
It seems Miwa and Tama are going, too.
Please make sure they don't
do anything dangerous.
I'm having our Hiroshi go
along, too, just in case...
This sounds like a real pain.
Hurry, Sensei!
Okay.
C'mon, hurry!
Wait a moment!
Sensei, hurry, hurry!
Okay, I got it!
Get ready!
Butt j—
Don't you dare!
Hey, don't run around!
It's Miwa-nee and Tama!
Mornin', Naru!
Yer late, Sensei!
Thanks for coming today!
What are you two wearing?
Those look like gym clothes.
Not just "like" 'em. They are gym clothes.
They're the best for swimmin'.
You're swimming in those?!
Well, yeah.
Isn't it hard to swim in regular clothes?
You strip down if ya like, Sensei.
Uh, no, I don't have a swimsuit.
C'mon! I said to hurry!
Hey, wait!
Hiro isn't here ye—
Okay, let's go.
Come on, kids, stick with Hiro-nii!
Okay!
This guy's just coming for fun, isn't he?
Let's go, everybody!
Today I'm gonna master the backstroke!
Hey!
Don't race around too much!
Don't worry.
We come to this beach every year.
It's too rocky to be a beach.
Play somewhere safer, like a sandy beach.
Sandy beaches are for little kids.
That's the point!
The footing... is really bad...
Sensei, what are you doing?!
Man, this is what's wrong with city slickers.
Will he be all right?
He oughta be fine.
Everyone uses this path.
All right, dive in!
Yeah!
Huh?
Woah, those're big!
Sea urchin!
Take that!
Cut it out, Naru!
Hey!
Find any neat fish, Hina?
Yeah, but the goggles keep
fogging up and I can't see them.
When that happens, wipe it with mugwort.
I keep mugwort leaves in here.
Mugwort extract helps prevent foggin'.
Wow!
Naru, you know everything!
You're like Gramma...
What d'ya mean, "Gramma"?
Oh, sorry... You didn't like that?
'Course not!
I'm only seven!
I'm sorry!
Sheesh, that's the problem with kids.
They just dunno how to enjoy the beach.
I see one! Take this!
Hiroshi Critical!
Woah! It's an octopus!
I got it!
Hiro-nii, yer so cool!
Hiro-nii, yer so uncool!
Sheesh, boys just dunno
how to play at the beach.
Sorry, Miwa-chan.
I'm a little tired.
You all right?
Don't go overdoin' it.
I'm going to rest a bit over by Sensei.
Sure.
Hey!
Are you all right, Tama?!
Your face is red!
Sorry about this.
I'm more the indoors type.
If you're the indoors type, then settle down.
Have some water for now.
Can you drink?
Yes.
What is this? I feel like
she's really staring at me.
Sensei...
Have you ever been so worried about
something, you couldn't sleep at night?
What's the matter?
Are you worried about something?
Not worried, exactly.
I'll be frank. What do you think about Hiro-nii?
Hiro?
What's this about?
Here we go!
I'm not sure what I think of him.
Ready, set, go!
He's close in age, and easy to talk
to, so... like a brother, I guess?
No... we're not that close.
He's just the guy who brings me my food.
Hold on...
Why would this glasses girl
be asking me such a thing?
I know!
She must have a crush on Hiro!
Now I get it. That's why she's
been acting so odd lately.
Though I'm not perfect, she still sees
me as a mentor, and wants my advice.
She does have her cute side.
Sensei?
I'll support them as much as I can.
Hiro's a great guy.
He's thoughtful, a good cook...
You don't often see such a great young man.
He's the perfect guy to go out w—
That's enough!
Whose fault do you think it is that
I'm having these sleepless nights?
I'm not one of those nasty fujoshi!
"Fujoshi"?
What do you mean?
Don't run like that!
It's dangero—
Sen... sei?
You're kidding, right?
Ta-da!
Look here, Naru!
It's a sea slug!
Woah! You're pretty daring to grab that.
You try holdin' it, Naru.
If you can hold it, yer an adult.
Adult...
Miwa-nee, yer mean!
Yer face makes me sick!
Sorry, sorry.
It's gross, but it's fine once ya get used to it.
It's all squishy!
I'm used to it!
Yep. That means yer an adult.
Hiro-nii, how's Sensei?
Oh...
Ah! How useless can you be?
Looks like he's still unconscious.
Okay, then that's good.
Naru!
Let's go someplace real fun.
Someplace real fun?
Yep, one that only adults can go to.
Oh, crap.
I blacked out again.
We should probably head back...
We haven't had lunch yet.
Hey, kids!
Time to get out!
What, already?
We're still playin'!
I knew they'd complain.
Hey!
Where's Naru?!
She was with Miwa-chan just a second ago.
Over there.
Here I go!
Miwa?!
That's dangerous! Stop it!
Ah, that's fun!
Hey, Miwa.
Sensei's sayin' something.
Yer right.
Maybe we should head back?
After one more jump, then?
Yeah.
But first...
Hey, Naru!
C'mon!
Hey! Wait! Hold it right there!
Why are you—
Stop! Naru!
Naru!
That was fun!
You done good!
That's my protégé for ya!
When I jumped, I heard Sensei cheerin' me on.
He yelled, "Naru!"
That's why I wasn't scared at all!
Cheering?
Now that you mention it,
he was sayin' somethin'.
Sensei?!
Hey... Sensei!
Honestly!
You did nothing but dangerous stuff!
Sorry, Sensei.
We won't do it no more, so don't be mad.
Hey, c'mon...
Sensei!
I've never felt like this before.
Before I came to this island, all I ever
really had to worry about was myself.
This is the first time I've been
so worried about someone else!
!
I'm going home!
Sensei!
Hey...
Sensei, I won't make you worry again!
Me neither!
Me either!
You guys...
Sensei!
I won't do nothin' dangerous no more!
I won't either!
Sensei! Sensei! Sensei!
The outsider's totally one of the gang now.
Stare...
Don't expect me to join in.
Sigh
Aww...
Don't look disappointed!
Cool
Breeze
Missed Call   1
Kawafuji
Fukue Airport
No use...
He's not answering his cell.
Out of
Range
I'm out of range again.
What'll we do?
Sheesh, this place is inconvenient.
I kinda like it here.
It's like everything is miniature. Teeny-weeny!
Kyousuke, are you making fun of it?
It's fine.
I'll go anywhere,
to meet Handa-san.
Miwa-chan! Miwa-chan!
Your hair's really wild!
It's 'cuz it's been so humid lately.
You always did have unruly hair.
Scruffy
He's just like me!
Oh, did you girls come to fish, too?
Sensei, your hair is intense...
Really?
It gets like this when I'm in good condition.
No, ain't it 'cuz of the humidity?
You both have similar hair qualities.
Even your hairstyle's the same.
Sensei, don't copy me!
"Copy"...
Maybe try goin' close-cropped?
No, that won't look good on me.
Oh, there's a bunch here today!
Mind if yer teacher joins ya?
Scruffy
Boy, it's tough when it's this muggy.
The same as the teacher?!
So glad I have straight hair...
Just close-cropped isn't enough,
obviously...
Ya got tengusa head!
Huh?
Tengusa
(red algae)