Hey! Come one, come all!
Cigarettes
I got shells for sale!
yen
Step right up!
His place should be around here.
Please make sure to find him today!
I'm sick of spending the night at campsites.
Yeah, yeah.
20 yen
What the heck is this?
I got shells for sale!
Step right up!
Gramma!
Oh, she's back.
Hey, step right up!
Dog
Why so competitive?
Playing shop keeper, huh?
What're you selling?
Shells.
May I have one, too?
Yes, here.
You like children?
For publicity's sake.
You're a pretty nasty guy.
Do you dislike them, Kawafuji-san?
I think I'd come to like her,
given another ten years.
That's not liking children, that's liking women.
Furthermore, I prefer mature women.
That's gross!
What're you doing?
Yuck, now my hand's slimy! It's filthy!
You trying to break my glasses?!
You dig it out with a needle like this, and eat it.
*Good children boil them before eating!
Ick ick ick!
Young lady...
Does someone named Handa
Seishuu live around here?
Handa...
Seishuu...
Not around here.
Wha? No way!
But...
there's a Sensei who goes
by a stylish name like that.
Sensei?
Our penmanship teacher.
Yeah, that's him!
Do you know where Handa-sensei's house is?
I'll tell you if you buy a shell.
Very shrewd...
Okay, sell me that one.
You have fine judgment, sir.
But, I can only sell this to someone wealthy,
like an eye-tea company head or major leaguer.
Well then.....
Would you accept this card?
C-Card?!
How much are you willing to sell for?
Since I want you to show me the way, I'll splurge.
I, I—
I'll give you a deal at a million yen, you thief!
That's not a deal at all.
Don't call me a thief.
It's my first time seein' one.
So, this is a card...
Here.
All right, young lady!
Show me the way to—
Wait, I'm gonna show this to Gramma.
Hold it! This comes first.
Stop it!
Let me go!
Hurry up and take me—
Where're you guys from?
Uh... well...
What's goin' on, Teacher?
They're suspicious.
Snatchin' a child?
Ya got tattoos.
Uh, that's not what's going on...
Call the fire brigade.
We got a village meetin' now.
Won't ya come tell us all 'bout it?
Get movin'!
Wait!
Kawafuji-san!
Barakamon
Yosonmon
Translation:
Guys From Tokyo
Thank you for this food.
Thank you for this food!
Wait, why are you guys
eating dinner at my house?
Dad and Mom went to the community
center for the village meeting.
Grampa, too.
And it's tastier than when eating alone, right?
Right?
I prefer eating alone.
Sensei, you've gained weight
since you came to the island.
No way!
Seriously.
The languid country air is ruining me!
A man oughta be a little plump.
You know, I've been wondering
about this for a while.
What's this scribbling?
Dog
Earlier, I met a fella with scribblin' on his arm.
Probably shady.
"Scribbling"? Isn't that a tattoo?
A flower and "Dog" and...
Dog
What are these round things?
Chocolate Marbles.
Was the guy's tattoo a hawk?
It was all muddled up, so I couldn't tell.
Actually, I've gotten a number
of texts since yesterday.
Kawafuji
I think that guy's my friend.
Since it fell into the sea,
Inbox
the keys are messed up, so I can't send a reply.
Never mind your phone...
What surprises me is you having a friend.
I'll hit you for that.
Sensei!
Oh, Miwa.
What's going on?
You really gotta ask?
These two...
Hey, you guys!
I said come in this way!
That's the front door!
Uh... it'd be better for me if
they entered through the front door.
Guests?
They're sayin' they're yer friends.
Hey!
Drunk
Kawa—
...fuji?
Why is he so drunk?
He was suspected of tryin' to kidnap
a child in broad daylight,
so they lectured him good at the village meetin'...
That is correct, sir!
But every time folks gather,
it turns into a drinkin' party.
No, I am truly sorry!
Ah, now I get it...
Handa!
I've been... so very worried about you.
A city boy like you, living in such a rural area...
What, you're crying now?
I was just so, so worried...
Kawafuji...
You care that much about me?
My Friend, Handa!
My Friend, Kawafuji!
My Friend Forever!
Kawafuji!
Handa...
Why, you!
How dare you ignore my calls?!
Are you fake?! A false friend?!
Sorry! My cell phone's broken.
Screw that! Find some other way to reach me!
Well... I thought you'd be able to make it here...
You forget how inconvenient the countryside is!
Why are you throwing up?!
Was it tough coming here from Tokyo?
With layovers, the flight took about three hours.
Wow. I don't know much about flying on planes.
I ain't been on one before.
Haven't you guys ever been to Tokyo?
Nope.
I've been to Nagasaki.
I've been to Hyougo.
Seriously? I can't believe it.
Sensei, we're outta konomon.
Go get more.
"Go get more"?
You think you can order your elders around?
It's yer house, so what's the problem?
C'mon, hurry!
You all get along very well.
Middle schoolers these days...
It don't seem like yer a friend of Sensei's...
Just taggin' along with the drunk?
I simply had to meet Handa-san.
This is who I am.
Kanzaki Kousuke
Kanzaki Kousuke, calligrapher.
I want a card, too!
I chose this career because of
my admiration for Handa-san.
Gimme one, too!
Wow, you look awfully young.
Me, too! Me, too! Me, too! Me, too!
I am eighteen.
I often get mistaken for a middle schooler.
Yay!
An eighteen-year-old calligrapher?
Feels like I've heard that somewhere...
Earlier, I worked up my courage and
entered the same competition as Handa-san.
It was the Tokyo Kasho Exhibition.
But I was so clueless,
I ended up taking grand prize from the one I admired.
I had always thought of Handa-san as above the
clouds, but he suddenly felt a lot closer to me.
Well, maybe Handa-san just
wasn't really trying that time?
Isn't he talking about that one?
From the mochi-gathering...
Yeah.
The Second-Place Calligraphy Incident.
What's a guy like that doin',
comin' to meet Sensei?
'Cause he wanted to see him lookin' mortified?
If Sensei were to learn his identity...
Is this enough konomon?
Oh! Handa-san, here's my card—
No!
What do you mean, "No"?
Don't we always eat this much?
We didn't mean the amount...
Also, that's too much!
You're hooked on the stuff!
Handa-san, you certainly are a funny one.
Hey, hey!
If he found out he lost
to such an obnoxious guy...
Sensei's got so much pride...
He could end up killing himself...
Handa-san, in that recent calli—
Hey, hey, look how late it is already!
That's right! You better get goin'!
Yer stayin' at an inn, right?
We stayed at the campground last night.
Oh, I see! Then you better
head back to the campin' village.
The road's dangerous at night.
Kawafuji's asleep anyway,
so just spend the night here.
Can we really?!
Thank goodness!
Go away, you!
I hated the campground. There were so many bugs.
And there's a lot I want to talk to you about.
What'll we do?!
He's rarin' to spend the night!
We'll have to spend the night,
too, and hold him off.
But I got a college advisin' session tomorrow.
What is it?
Any friend of Sensei's is a friend of mine.
I got club myself.
Here's a token of our friendship.
What is it?
Filthy Monster Ball!
What've you done?!
Waaah! My precious shield bugs!
Don't keep weird pets!
Too loud...
!
Get out!
Sensei, don't! If you excite them...
It stinks!
I tried to warn ya!
Hiro-nii!
Yeah!
Here!
There!
Usin' this, you can catch 'em
before they let off stink.
You guys sure know some
dicey underhanded tricks.
It came in real handy here,
so don't call it "dicey."
I'm sick of this!
I wanna go home!
Anyhow, you really should leave for today.
The stink'll be attractin' other bugs.
Well then, I'll be back tomorrow.
Sure. I'll be waiting.
Oh, Handa-san.
Can I... call you "Sensei," too?
Sure, if you want.
Crisis averted!
So that was Kanzaki Kousuke...
He doesn't look at all like a calligrapher.
But his nasty side kinda shows through.
Hang on a minute!
Hang on!
You knew who he was?!
From: Kawafuji
Sub: Answer your phone!
We're not acquainted,
but Kawafuji sent me a text.
"I'm bringing Kanzaki Kousuke, the kid who won
grand prize in the calligraphy competition."
"He's a bit quirky, so be ready."
See?
"See," nothing!
We were thinkin' you'd be all upset about it!
Oh, is that right?
Well, it's not as if I'm unbothered by it.
I do have some envy, too.
But I feel more at ease somehow.
Sensei...
Now, let's go catch the rest of the shield bugs.
Ayup!
I'm lost.
Sorry to barge in again today.
You okay with tea?
Oh, don't trouble yourself.
Kawafuji didn't come today?
Bright Camping Village
He has a terrible hangover and can't stand up.
Well, that's the thing about that guy.
In whatever he does, he has bad timing.
Drinking tea in this heat?
Black soy tea really is the best.
Did Kawafuji-san tell you anything about me?
Like how you won a grand prize
and let it go to your head?
What a mean thing to say.
I truly admire you, Handa-sensei.
Here, take a look at my collection.
Introduction to Calligraphy
Quiet & Movement
Calming the Mind
Modern Culture
Guide to Calligraphy                                                     Heart of Calligraphy
I picked up every book I could
find that had you in it.
Introduction to
Calligraphy
Guide to
Quiet & Movement
Calming the Mind
You're a genius calligrapher with
a calligraphy expert as your father.
Cloud
Magazine
In every single book, your calligraphy is considered
beautiful and faithful to the fundamentals.
See your smug face in this pin-up?
Calligrapher
Handa Seishuu
You couldn't make an expression
like that without self-confidence!
And here's one of you in a suit.
Were you going for the impression of black ink?
Handa Seishuu
What is this?
It's extremely embarrassing...
Do you see now?!
You are who I aspire to be.
I especially treasure the comments that you made.
Cloud
Spring Sky
"As I inhale deeply of the refined air,
I address my paper and brush,
and they respond to me, affirmingly."
Stop!
Don't read that out loud!
"To me, calligraphy is
the act of luring myself into catharsis..."
What's "karta-sushi"?
Karta
Karta                                       Sushi
Shut up.
Don't console me wordlessly!
This one's even lovelier.
Stop The Humiliation!
Here's what I'll do!
That's mean!
Who's being mean?!
You came to laugh at me, didn't you?!
N-No, I did not!
I wanted to hear your famous lines live.
I even brought a voice recorder!
Are you a maniac?!
And after seeing your entry at the Kasho
Exhibition, I knew I had to meet you.
What are you doing out here in the country?
Isn't the calligraphy you submitted to the exhibition
one that you wrote after coming to the island?
Sensei...
Come back to Tokyo with us.
Man, my head hurts.
Hey, what're you guys up to?
Sorry 'bout yesterday.
We came to see Kanzaki-kun...
He 'round?
Oh, he went to Handa's place.
What, already?!
What about it?
Did you come to warn him not to
say anything unnecessary to Handa?
Well, yeah, we did.
You're going to a lot of trouble.
It's no fun looking after an adult, is it?
We ain't particularly lookin' after him!
Say no more.
I know that feeling well.
Despite appearances, the guy's a real handful.
He's no good without somebody
supporting him from the shadows.
Handa and I have been friends since middle school.
He's always been bad at social interactions.
Are you some kind of idiot?
Anytime he opened his mouth,
he'd say something high-handed.
I'm just so...
He'd get depressed easily, and wall himself off.
A barrier?
And then, he even went and
punched a gallery director.
It's been tough covering for him...
How is it I can picture his school days so easily?
Since I'd pictured the countryside as a place
where associating with others was important,
I assumed that he'd give up
and come back right away.
He must be having a lot of fun, living here.
Could you look after him a little longer?
If ya know Sensei so well,
why'd ya come bringin' Kanzaki-kun?
Sensei was feelin' mighty down after
losin' the grand prize to him.
My head again...
Don't fake sick!
I'm an art dealer.
Before being my friend, Handa's a money tree.
"Money tree"?
So I'll be in trouble if he doesn't
produce good works, right?
Since he came to this island,
he's been searching for something.
But he's probably floundering,
not knowing what it is.
In order for a person to mature,
don't they need a rival?
Now then...
I've got a hangover, so I'll spend the day sleeping.
Tell Handa I'm coming tomorrow.
He does seem like you'd expect
a friend of Sensei's to be.
Lions smack their own cubs down into valleys.
Are they like that?
But first, how does calligraphy
have winners and losers?
It's not a martial art.
Please return to Tokyo, and do calligraphy
seriously again, like you used to.
Wait a minute!
I came to this island to boost
my skill in calligraphy.
I can't go back until I get results.
Results...?
What "results" are you talking about?
I'd done calligraphy since grade school,
but since it was just boring practice
day after day, I was planning to quit.
Ward Residents Art Center
At that time,
I reluctantly visited a calligraphy exhibition,
and saw calligraphy you had written.
"What pretty calligraphy!" I thought.
But now, you're not getting results.
You're getting worse.
Worse?!
Haven't you realized it?
It's like you're pointlessly attempting
to add too much individuality.
Your writing is just forceful.
It's not like you at all!
Really...?
The fact that you lost to me is proof of that!
Sure, I expected you to feel mortified,
but you have no idea how
much you're degenerating!
This environment is ruining you!
Wait a minute!
Let's go back to Tokyo!
Now, look...
Writing calligraphy people will
acknowledge is everything.
Aren't you the one who said that?
Your calligraphy is just plain dull.
For one still so young,
your calligraphy is highly conformist.
...better described as copybook-style...
Sensei, please, listen to me!
Did you even attempt to scale
the wall of mediocrity?
Instead of fussin' over that stuff,
I'd rather have fun writin'.
Let's go back, Sensei!
You can't stay in a place like this!
Acknowledged? By whom?
Sensei! Sensei!
Sen—
Shut up!
What do you want from me?!
I win a prize, but get told it's dull!
I write good calligraphy, but don't win a prize!
I don't know anymore.
I don't know what the correct answer is...
Paper airplanes?
My collection!
Who would do this?!
Amazing!
Your planes really fly great!
They fly when the wind blows.
Sensei!
Yer flyin'!
Quit messing around, kids!
Hey, say something, Sense—
Go on ahead.
My calligraphy that you call pretty
is well-behaved calligraphy,
written the way my dad told me.
I don't mind if you get mad.
I want...
to write calligraphy only Handa Seishuu can write.
I don't know what the correct answer is,
but letting your words goad me
into returning to Tokyo feels wrong.
I want to change myself.
Here.
Hey, you guys, that's dangerous!
Come down from there!
Ayup!
Okay!
Go on ahead and wait for me a little longer.
I'll catch up right away, riding on the wind.
Sensei!
Could you repeat those words once m—
Oh, crap!
That was a better hit than I expected.
Naru, go call the village chief!
Hina, you go get ice!
Ayup!
Too bad...
He's still got some growing up to do.
I'd better do my best, too.
Why's this guy at our house?
A lot happened.
Havin' a young man visit gives your
mother a reason to cook dinner.
Old hags shouldn't try for sex appeal.
I'm gonna knock yer block off!
Translation: I'll hit you hard enough to dislocate your jaw!
Oh! That's right, Sensei!
Earlier, Naru was distributin' these
magazines throughout the village.
Yer real famous, Sensei!
Uh, er...
Please autograph this.
Does your mother have a grudge against me?
Sorry, I guess...
But there's no way he'd have an autogra—
Oh, he does...
Uh... you said she was distributing
them throughout the village?
Sensei, we saw them!
I knew it...
These books're from a bookstore in Tokyo!
Gimme your autograph!
That's a real big deal!
I ain't got a signboard, so sign my T-shirt.
He ain't called Sensei for nothin'!
To me, calligraphy is...
As I inhale deeply of the refined air...
No! Stop it!
Luring myself into catharsis...
I'm going back to Tokyo!
Filthy Monster Ball!
Good evening.
Man 1
Don't keep weird pets!
Man 2            Man 1
Over there!
Too loud...
Man 3
Help me!
Man 4            Man 3
I'm going back to Tokyo!
Hey, Hiroshi! Hiroshi!
Isn't that dangerous?
Sensei, is it okay to let go?!
Their army...
is increasin'!