We're goin' fishin'!
I'm not happy with this, Handa-kun.
With what?
I took off five whole days to come to this island,
but all I've gotten to do is look for your house,
then suffer a hangover after a bunch
of strange old guys got me drunk.
I want my vacation back.
You brought it on yourself.
We're fishin' 'cuz you said you wanted
to make the most of yer last day here.
Listen, middle schooler...
By "make the most of,"
I meant going sightseeing. Get it?
What sights?
Dunno any sightseein' spots here.
I'm not happy, either!
This was my big chance to see you
write calligraphy at close proximity!
I can't believe we're outdoors!
Are even his vacation goals indoors?
What's wrong, Hiro?
You don't look well.
I had to listen to his theories
on calligraphy all night.
I started doing the art back in grade school!
There was this U-23 exhibition...
I'm very particular about my brush!
I didn't get a wink of sleep.
I wanna stay indoors!
Bamboo Pole
Fish Hooks with
Artificial Lure
Here's your tackle.
What do we catch with this?
Bait
Basket
Horse mackerel.
You don't just put bait on a hook?
I've never seen these before!
Wait, is this yer first time fishin'?!
It's a bamboo stalk!
Yeah.
And you, Kawa-san?
Don't lump me in with those city boys.
I go for bass!
Uh, that won't help catchin' horse mackerel.
Bigger covers smaller.
But ocean ain't river.
Get it off me!
Naru.
Put bait in this.
I can't touch it.
Ayup!
Huh?
There's bait on the hooks, too...
Eww...
It's fake?
Come on, grab it!
The pole smells fishy!
I can't take this!
It's too high! Let it down!
Quit your bellyachin'!
Speak proper Japanese!
I didn't come to teach city folk fishin'.
Aw, shaddup!
I'm goin' up above, so good luck, Miwa.
Yer runnin' away, Hiro-nii?!
I'm a man of the sea.
I'm beyond horse mackerel.
I go for...
hisan-iwo.
Hisan-iwo!
Hisan-iwo?
Hisan-iwo! Hisan-iwo!
Yer amazin', Hiro-nii.
Good luck! I hope ya catch one!
What's "hisan-iwo"?
Beats me.
Maybe a "hideous-sad" fish?
Barakamon
Hisan-Iwo
Translation:
A High-Grade Fish
First, toss in ground bait.
Thanks.
Then, drop the line where you threw the bait.
When the end of the pole wiggles...
Do like this.
Wow!
Gramma said it'd be good fishin' today.
Great, I'll fish!
Me, too.
We'll have fried horse mackerel for dinner!
It feels like I got one!
Pull it up!
I caught two whole fish.
A big catch!
Naru.
Ayup!
Yer roles are reversed...
Check it out, Handa. I got three!
What? I won't lose!
I got a bite, too!
It's strong! What a pull!
It's definitely a big one!
Ahahahahahahahaha!
I'm a genius at fishing as well as calligraphy!
Behold, ignoramuses!
See our difference in status!
It's stuck in the shoal.
Shoal?
Reelin' in the Earth, huh? Yer real good!
Look, wharf roaches!
It can't be...
Gobs of 'em!
Naru has obtained Slightly Longish Stick!
Gotcha!
Hina, hold out yer hand.
No!
It'll be fine.
It'll be fine!
No! They bite!
I'm sick of this!
I stink, I can't fish, I'm hot... I wanna go home!
But I just landed that huge catch.
We can't leave yet.
I want to write calligraphy with you, Sensei!
W-Wait... Hey!
You hate outdoor activities too, don't you?
Let's go back to your house!
I don't want to
write calligraphy with you.
Why would you say that?!
You'll just say I've gotten worse again.
Kousuke!
Did you really tell him that?!
Well...
It's the truth.
Can't you see anything from any
viewpoint besides your own?!
This is why you're in a slump!
A slump? You can't write?
It's because he was looking
at your earlier calligraphy.
You haven't gotten worse, Handa.
If you had, you wouldn't have
placed at all, much less second.
Kousuke was focused on your earlier work.
So, after your style changed,
he got anxious about losing his model.
Just look at them.
That's what I'm saying.
What's this about?
Children imitate their superiors, right?
Handa, have you seen Kousuke's calligraphy?
No, I don't look at that stuff.
I figured.
His calligraphy looks just like yours.
And your calligraphy is just like your dad's.
You're both only faithful to the fundamentals.
But I got first place with that,
so aren't the fundamentals best?
Was that a subtle dig at my father?
The role of the young
is to break new ground without fear of failure!
The director!
Remain in memories, not record books!
Lose the battle, win the war!
Only One is better than Number One!
Good-selling beats prize-winning!
That one's your wish!
Bring me money...
He's being consumed!
Sensei!
I learned from Miwa-nee.
Use this.
Wow, did you tie that, Hina?
Sensei, use mine, too.
You made one, too?
Mine is super-ultra.
It'll catch gobs!
You can't catch anything with that!
Is this "breaking new ground"?
Well, yeah, pretty much...
That's the incarnation of failure!
Hey, don't laugh so much.
A child made it.
But, it's just so simple-minded!
Tackle!
You... brat!
I'll let you off for today.
They're having fun down there...
Hiro-nii, ya got ground bait?
Huh?
Yer already out?
Hina tossed it all.
Were they able to fish right?
Found my glasses!
In the end, they've just been
talkin' calligraphy here, too.
All this about bein' bad or not.
Ain't it enough for someone
good at it to be good?
I guess when ya reach the top,
there ain't nowhere left to go.
Maybe I won't catch hisan-iwo today, either.
Guess it's really impossible 'round here.
But the village chief was sayin'
he saw someone catch one here.
Hey, Hiroshi! Caught any hisan-iwo yet?
Not a one.
Wanna call it a day?
Hiroshi, try usin' this.
What's that? It looks like cursed tackle.
Uh, sorry.
All right, it's my last cast,
so I'll give it a try.
Make sure ya say "Ebisu."
I know, I know.
What are they talking about?
A magic spell.
They say, if ya say "Ebisu" while castin'
yer line, you'll catch a hisan-iwo.
Ebisu, as in one of the Seven Lucky Gods?
'Cuz Ebisu's holdin' a hisan-iwo.
Hisan-iwo is snapper?!
Rock snapper, to be precise.
But they fish for snapper in open sea.
If you could catch them at places like this,
then anyone could be a fisherman.
Don't knock it.
But, if he catches one, we'll
have snapper sashimi for dinner.
Ebisu!
Now they're motivated?
Of course!
How can we leave this island
without eating anything tasty?
Nothing's biting.
Yeah.
You guys forgot that you're trying
to fish with that hook, didn't you?
All right, let's pack up.
Aww!
I'm going to clean up, so hold onto it.
Me?!
You haven't caught anything yet, right?
W-Wait!
Aw, ...
Huh?!
I got a bite!
What?
Miwa, the net!
I'm on it!
Is it thanks to Ebisu?
All right, let's help, too!
Hey, you're in the way!
Dummy, you can't land such
a big one by yourself.
I can, too!
You just want to steal my thunder, don't you?!
Ebisu! Ebisu!
Quit yelling!
All right!
We got it!
It's huge!
That sure was a big one!
Yeah, no kiddin'!
And that "plop."
The "big one" went "plop"!
My belly hurts.
The hook broke up in midair!
Let's go.
Well, we caught a bunch of
horse mackerel, so that's fine.
We'll fry them at my place.
They're good pickled, too.
Let's go, Sensei.
For some reason...
Since I came to this island, there are times
when I really want to write calligraphy.
I feel something well up,
and my hands tremble.
Right now,
I feel the same way.
These are the ones Sensei caught.
So...
Today, to celebrate our visit to this island...
Good work, everyone!
Don't ignore me!
Let's dig in!
These fish have ink on them...
That's wreckage from breaking new ground.
I would rather eat snapper, but oh well.
You guys work hard and grow,
and make me wealthy.
You always did have that side to you.
To Kawafuji-san, I'm just a commodity.
Do you know what he meant
by "breakin' new ground"?
Beats me.
Look in the room.
Peeking without asking again...
Me next.
Pretty good!
I always did like yer calligraphy, Sensei,
but this one's the best!
SNAPPER
Fukue Airport
Flight 635 to Fukuoka will begin boarding at 10:20.
Sheesh.
You didn't need to come see us off.
Passengers, please proceed to the boarding gate.
It's only about three hours to Tokyo.
Well, I can understand the reluctance to part,
What's this?
Kankoro mochi.
but you didn't need to make this much fuss...
It tastes great if ya heat it in a toaster oven.
Look, Kawafuji!
It's written "Happiki Kaminari"
(Eight Lightning Beasts),
but pronounced "Hacchi-Kankan."
These TV rocks are a rock revolution!
What did you really come here for?
Oh, what's that?
Why are the locals here so hyper?
There's time before your departure,
so you should buy some souvenirs, Kawafuji-kun.
Yeah...
I appreciate all you did for me.
Don't mention it.
Sensei's friends are very welcome here.
The village children normally
only interact with local people,
so they enjoyed playing
with people from the city.
Look, ain't this amazin'?
There's somethin' over here!
There's a bunch of toys.
The airport's amazin'!
It's like Santa Claus's house.
Wanna take one with you?
Nah, I'll pass.
Say, which product is this island known for?
Well, let's see...
Kankoro mochi,
Camellia candy,
oval squid, sea urchin,
Gotou udon,
Gotou beef...
I can't take that much home.
Is there anything besides food?
How about a cell phone strap?
They're pretty standard.
Gotou Exclusive
Baramon-kun
That's totally not cute!
Take back a bunch of Baramon-kun
for your friends in Tokyo.
I don't have any friends,
so I'll just buy one for me.
I'm...
sorry.
For what?
I'll buy one, too.
I'm gonna buy this!
Buy it?
Don't you mean, make me buy it?
I'm beggin' you, Sensei!
It's my dyin' request...
Don't invoke the next world at your age.
But I really wanna give this to Kawafuji!
Honestly, you...
sure know what he really likes!
I don't like those!
You bought a lot of souvenirs.
I bragged to my coworkers about coming
to Gotou, so I had to keep up appearances.
Flight 635 to Fukuoka will now begin boarding.
It's time.
Sorry I couldn't provide you any hospitality at all.
Please board at gate number one.
I already know you're insensitive.
Well, I was just glad to see you doing well.
I can give a good report to Handa-sensei.
You see my dad?
Occasionally, in connection with work.
Although he sent you away, he was still worried.
I see...
What's wrong?
Why so surprised?
It's just... knowing you,
I thought you'd keep playing the rebel
and say something like, "As if he'd worry."
Lately I've been thinking,
maybe Dad doesn't hate me after all.
You're only just realizing that now?
Strict isn't the same as hateful.
From the outside, I'd say he's pretty doting.
What?! He is not!
Call once in a while.
Kawafuji...
Has Kawa-san started boarding already?!
No, not yet.
But soon.
His glasses!
His glasses got him!
I knew he'd get caught.
That's why you wanted to...
Not my glasses, my belt!
Too funny!
He's sayin' something.
Was he hiding a knife in those glasses?
Kawafuji, I'm embarrassed as your friend.
Sensei.
Thank you very much.
Although I did all those rude things,
I'm truly happy to have met you.
It was very educational.
Educational?
This isn't a school trip.
If we continue on the same path,
we're likely to meet again.
I'm also happy to have met you.
Instead of being jealous
of some guy I don't know,
I feel better after meeting you face to face.
Come visit again.
Yes! I will definitely come again!
Definitely!
I'm dying! Are they trying to kill me?
The metal detector's capture
ability is tremendous!
I'm kinda embarrassed, myself...
Oh, no!
I forgot to give 'em the souvenir
Grampa sent with me!
There's still time!
Go, Naru!
Ayup!
Wait...
She shouldn't have anything metal on her.
There they come.
Kawa-san sees us.
He's wavin'.
It'll be lonely without 'em.
And we only just met them.
Sensei's even more...
No fair! You got a drink!
Gimme!
You jealous?
His adaptability's the real deal.
Gimme!
Tokyo, huh...
Somethin' wrong?
You wanna go to Tokyo too, Hiro-nii?
Not so much that I wanna go to Tokyo...
But I was thinkin', the day'll come
when we'll be leavin' the island, too.
I'm in my last year of high school,
so I oughta consider that reality.
Hey, I was having a serious scene!
They're flyin'!
Bye-bye!
We'd be over capacity.
Kawafuji-kun returned his rental car,
so take the bus home.
Bye-bye!
Hey!
Wait!
There's room for us in there!
Hold it!
Bet you'll be lonely with your friends gone.
No...
I can look forward to seeing them again.
What was the souvenir from Naru?
So that's what set it off.
Naru
Let's come again.
Yes.
Hey...
Next time...
I'll come alone.