August
September
The role of the young
is to break new ground without fear of failure!
Break new ground, huh...
Feather
Okay...
Porcelain Spoon
Sensei!
What're you tryin' to do?
Rice Bowl
It's Naru's birthday?
Shh!
If Naru hears, it won't be a surprise!
We thought we'd all throw a party for her.
You're an adult, so contribute a thousand yen.
Happy Birthday
Party fees for a kid's birthday party?!
Not party fees. It's the cake fee.
We can't buy a whole one with our pocket change.
Hiro-nii will bring the food this evening.
Sensei, you get a present for her, too.
A present?!
Cake! Cake!
Wait, I have to write today...
Feather
Rice Bowl
Porcelain Spoon
Well...
I guess that's enough for today.
Barakamon
Onde
Translation:
Buddhist Prayer Dance
Your present is...
a teddy bear!
It's a punching bag!
A ribbon!
Yahoo! It's perfect for
wrapping around my waist!
Look, a hand mirror!
Yay! Laser Beam!
Too bright!
None of those suit her.
What would she like?
Shut up, cicada!
All right, I got it!
I caught a cicada!
Kenta, got a moment?
Sensei?
Need somethin'?
Well...
I kind of need a favor...
This is the only present I can think of.
Could I have a rhinoceros beetle?
No way!
One! Just one!
I'll pay you ten yen!
That's a lot for a kid, right?!
Yer bein' a pest, Sensei!
This present's for Naru, right?
I'm givin' her rhinoceros beetles!
Just one won't hurt, right?
No!
Rustle...
I'm gonna give her a hundred
of 'em to make an insect bed!
That's more like a punishment.
Besides, I don't wanna give the
same present as someone else!
Well, that's true...
What are you giving her, Ichiro and Jiro?
Don't make up names for us!
We're givin' her sweets!
You've all thought on it.
You oughta think hard on it, too, Sensei!
I'll give her a stag beetle!
If you can catch that many rhinoceros beetles,
then a stag beetle should be even easier, right?
Lend me the net.
Bug catchin' ain't as easy as ya think, Sensei.
Heck, life ain't that easy.
You call it easy,
but they're tough to find.
That's because you're children, isn't it?
With my adult's height,
I can see higher up, so it'll be easy!
Sensei, yer gettin' real irritatin'.
Found one right away!
Aww, it's a female.
Hey!
I spotted it!
Yer too slow!
The battle ain't over 'til the beetle's caught!
What?!
If ya can't catch even one rhinoceros beetle,
Naru's gonna be fed up with ya!
So disappointed...
I don't exactly care, but I'm still irritated.
Kenta, there's one over here!
I got it!
I ain't gonna lose!
Yes!
I did it! I caught a rhinoceros beetle—
Wait, no I didn't! What is this?!
That's a drone beetle, doofus!
Sensei can't catch nothin'!
Let's go that way!
Yay!
You  kids!
I won't lose to you!
A greater stag beetle!
It's a bit high up.
All right!
Formation Beta!
Almost there...
Y-You're heavy...
I can't hold up!
Ow, ow, ow...
Where's Kenta?
What are you guys doing?
Sensei, you didn't leave yet?
Don't you mean, "Thank you"?
I can't leave without catching one.
With this, I'm unbeatable.
I can catch any bug, no matter how high up.
All right! I've got my present!
Sensei?
Can you lend me the net real quick?
You came bug catchin' when
you won't even touch 'em?!
You jerk! It might bite me,
or it could carry some weird disease!
They don't bite, and don't carry diseases!
Apologize to the beetle!
Up close, it's even more gross than I imagined!
Why is it so glossy?!
It's just like a cockroach!
They ain't the same at all, stupid!
Anyway, give me the net, now!
No!
I think it might've bit me!
Could a guy like this catch bugs?
Gah! It hurts! It hurts! It hurts, I think!
No way.
Amazin'!
Look at this, Kenta!
It's a Hercules beetle!
What's one doin' here?
Someone must've been
keepin' it, but it got away!
It wouldn't be here otherwise!
Why, is it really that amazing?
It's real amazin'!
They showed 'em on TV!
They cost 20,000 yen!
20,000 for a bug?!
Sensei, lend us the ladder!
We'll join forces to catch it!
Naru'll be thrilled to get such big game!
Yeah, really!
20,000 for a kid's present...
Carefully...
Go carefully, Kenta.
Yeah.
No good... I can't reach!
Sensei!
Me?! No, I can't, I can't!
We'll hold the ladder!
An' we'll let Naru know how good you did!
We'll give her the big game together!
We're beggin' ya, Sensei!
Sensei, go for it!
Go for it!
Keep goin', Sensei!
It's so gross...
Shut up! Just catch it, now!
I caught it!
We did it!
Hooray!
Wait! Hey!
Hercules!
Don't let go!
H-Hey!
How can ya fall twice in one day?
Yer clumsiness is a talent in itself.
I'm never trusting you guys again.
So, got the Hercules?!
Yeah.
I knew I couldn't let it get away,
so I held on tight to the net.
Yay!
Huh?
It ain't movin'.
It's...
dead...
It can't be dead!
You smashed it!
You're kidding!
I can't believe you smashed the Hercules!
Stupid, stupid, stupid!
Yer dyin' next!
You're that upset?
You'd say that because of some bug?
But we were gonna give it to Naru!
Don't cry! Sheesh!
Hurkules
I really am sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Here, Sensei!
I'll give ya one I caught.
Are you sure?
Yeah. 'Cuz you worked hard for Naru's sake.
I never met an adult who'd play
seriously like you, Sensei.
I'm gonna have gobs of fun this summer!
Me, too!
You guys...
Grab it from the back.
Like this?
Right!
I did it! I can hold it!
Now I'm one step closer to your level!
I never had any intention
of playing with you guys.
I just hate losing.
I'll be going at it seriously
from now on, so be ready!
What're you doin', dummy?!
Naru's Turning 7
My house...
Naru-chan
Happy Birthday
is set up for the party?
Yer late, Sensei!
How did you guys get into my house?!
You underestimate us.
How many years do ya think
we've used this as our base?
I have another of these,
so you can have this back.
Is that...
A duplicate key!
I went to the hardware store for a duplicate
bike key, and it was surprisingly cheap!
I made five of 'em.
I have one, too.
Huh? It's unlocked today.
Hiro! You too?!
Wait, if there are five of them...
Who has the last one?
I lost it.
Maybe while playin' in the hills out back?
Sensei, do you have a present ready?
Oh, right, a present...
I brought bubble wrap!
I picked up some peacock feathers.
You guys really know what makes Naru tick.
You got bubble wrap, Miwa-chan?
I thought about that, too.
But those feathers are great!
Really?
I shoulda tried lookin' around—
Naru's coming!
Oh, no!
Get ready, everyone!
This is my first time throwing a birthday party.
We couldn't have done it without you, Sensei.
Me?
Let's do this every year from now on!
Did I do something?
Shoot off the cracker when she comes in.
Hey!
Naru!
Happy Birthday!
Oh, that's right! It's my birthday!
First, your present from Sensei!
Naru's Turning 7
Uh, no, I'll give mine later!
Don't say that!
Hey! Stop it!
Got it!
Here! From Sensei.
Ticket to do
anything you say
Cut Here
One
time
What is this?! A grade schooler's
Mother's Day present?!
And there's just one! So stingy!
Listen, you guys...
Naru, it's okay to be mad!
Ticket to do
anything you say
One time
Yes!
I'm frightened by how thrilled you sound...
Isn't that great, Naru?
I keep watering these sunflowers, even though
I have no idea who planted them or when.
If I left them alone, they'd probably
grow up fine on their own...
Climbing up there again?
You know that's dangerous.
Grampa's goin' on a grave visit.
He said to bring you along, Sensei.
Grave visit?
Yep!
Sensei! This way, this way!
Oh, right...
It's already Obon season...
Sensei!
Over 'ere, Sensei!
Good of ya to come!
Are you sure you want an outsider
like me at your family grave?
I hafta go to the fields,
so I was thinkin' I'd have you keep
vigil over the gravesite flame.
Firecrackers?!
That's gotta be bad omen!
That's normal 'round here!
Huh, a custom?
Well, take care of the rest!
See you later!
You're going already?
Naru knows the ropes, so just do as she says!
Now, off to the fields!
He just dumped it on me...
Kotoishi
Family
Grave
I've never made a proper grave visit before.
I don't know who's resting here,
but I hope you'll treat me well today.
Sensei, first ya gotta set the lan'ern.
The "lan'ern"?
See, those!
Ah, paper lanterns.
Lan'ern!
Now that you mention it,
all the graves have one.
Until this flame goes out,
we mustn't leave the grave.
These are candles that burn for two hours.
We need to stay here for that long?
I got these in case we get bored!
So you do that, too...
Mind if I pay a visit, too?
Oh! Yasuba!
I came to offer an incense stick.
I was friends with Naru's gramma, y'know.
Somehow or other, I managed
to live through this past year.
That's kinda depressing...
There, much obliged.
Sensei, ya must have it rough in this heat.
With an outsider like me here,
Naru's grandma probably can't rest easy.
That ain't so.
Just look at this candle.
See how the flame's dancin' up and down?
Yeah, it is...
That means her gramma's smilin' down on ya.
Have faith in yerself.
Guess I'll do my best, if it'll make
the master of this grave happy.
Ayup!
Do you have a lighter?
I have matches.
Fireworks again?!
They're parachutes!
Fallin' umbrellas!
Hey, they're coming this way!
I did it! Midair catch!
That's our Miwa-chan!
Running wild without regard
for anyone she's disturbing!
Man, it's hard to run in a yukata.
I wanna do it, too!
Sorry, those were the last fallin' umbrellas.
Let's do somethin' else.
C'mon, Sensei, give us some reaction!
You can't just ignore us!
That's foul play!
He's telling us to help?
Fine, we'll help, we'll help!
Stop giving us the evil eye!
So this is different from Obon in Tokyo?
Completely different.
For starters, we don't visit in the evening,
and we don't offer uncooked rice.
We also don't set off fireworks,
or wear yukata, or hang paper lanterns.
You don't?!
Kotoishi
Family
Grave
The gold gravestone lettering is strange, too!
Yer kiddin'! They ain't
gold everywhere in Japan?!
Well, since I rarely make grave visits,
I can't exactly talk like I'm
an expert on the customs.
Well, we only come to visit
graves during Obon, too.
And we really only come to set off fireworks.
Oh, and to see the onde.
Onde?
Pardon me...
D'ya mind if we proceed past your gravesite?
That's the onde. They dance at each family
grave that's had a death since last Obon.
They're kinda scary...
What does that mean, translated into Japanese?
It ain't exactly a foreign language.
What's this? Why'd he stop?
Also, isn't he looking my way?
He is looking at me!
Have I done something wrong?!
You should see the look on your face!
Sensei, you frighten too easily.
Hiro?!
You're in the troop, too?!
They were shorthanded, so I'm filling in.
Hiro-senpai!
We have to hurry to the next one!
My feet are killin' me.
Just three more. Hang in there!
Later, Sensei. I still have dancing to do.
Sure. Good luck.
Don't follow me!
Why not?
I want to watch you dance.
Sensei's gradually starting to fit in here.
He's totally actin' as Naru's guardian.
I've tried to avoid thinking about it much,
but didn't Sensei come here because he
punched someone eminent in calligraphy?
What if his punishment were lifted?
Tama...
Finished your summer homework yet?
Well, to a degree.
Lemme copy it!
Miwa-chan...
Ah! Yer late, Sensei!
Fireworks! Fireworks!
It's smoky...
Heya, Sensei.
Mind if we offer incense?
Village Chief?
Naru's gramma took good care
of us while she was alive.
Oh, from Kinoshita General Store.
Mind if I offer incense?
Please, go ahead.
Hey! Miwa!
Why'd you leave our gravesite
alone to goof off here?!
Geh! Dad!
Sensei, tell him ya made me come here!
You're nuts! No way!
Sis, what are you doing?
Mom's been looking for you.
Aki...
How did you know I was here?
Mom told me to take
incense to Naru's grandma.
May I offer some this year, too?
Sure!
Naru's grandma is really popular.
Yes, she is.
Each year, people take turns paying her a visit.
Since Naru's grandpa is busy,
until now, Naru's had to keep
vigil over the flame by herself.
Come to think of it,
I've never seen Naru's parents...
Sensei! A pinwheel!
Hey!
Today's been more fun than usual!
Give me a break, you brat.
It was always boring waiting
for grampa to get back,
but today I don't wanna leave.
Then spend the night here!
I bet I know why.
It must be 'cuz you're here, Sensei.
I wanna play, too!
I never realized it since she's
always with someone...
But she gets lonely just like anyone else.
If I left her alone, she'd probably
grow up fine on her own...
Yay!
But maybe I'll look after her when I have time.
The flame went out.
It's already time to leave?
The vigil went by fast.
We're goin' now?
Your grandpa hasn't come back yet.
So I'll extend it.
All right!
Sensei's so sweet!
Shut up!
Gramma!
I'm gonna keep playin' here!
You're that happy?
Oh!
Look, Sensei, look!
Gramma's smilin' too!
Heya, Sensei.
Pooch-san!
Did you come here to fish for dinner?
Dogs don't eat crayfish.
You're looking like one of the locals,
fishing at the lake like this.
Oh, no... I'm still learning.
The villagers seem to like you too, Sensei.
Why not move here permanently?
I'm afraid I can't do that.
I see.
Well, when there's a place
that accepts you as you are,
don't you feel like it's safe
to attempt the impossible?
Pooch-san...
Treat me to lobster once you're
a big-shot calligrapher!
So you do eat crayfish!
Don't tell the shopkeeper, okay?
That's what he said in my dream.
It was just a dream, but it still made me happy.
Huh...
Pooch is female.