Yeah, it's finished.
I'll mail it within the week,
so make sure you get it.
I'm truly glad that I could
write good calligraphy.
Ever since I came here,
I've had all kinds of inspiration.
Naruka Competition Entry
"Star"
Artist: Handa Seishuu
Name: Handa Sei
Address, Phone:
Kawafuji House of the Arts
The energy of nature is amazing!
Unlike in Tokyo, I have fun writing here.
Hey, are you listening, Kawafuji?
In Call
Hey!
You're here early, Director.
Thank you for taking the time to come.
Is his writing coming along well?
Her certainly talks like it is.
Rather than producing the same
beautiful writing as someone else,
I want Handa-kun to master calligraphy
that only he could write.
Art that instantly brings him
to mind when you see it.
Who can say?
Personally, I'd like to have him back sooner,
but it seems he doesn't intend to return
until he gets results at an exhibition.
Does he feel remorseful about hitting me?
I can't really say.
If my forgiveness will persuade him to return,
then maybe it's time we have him come back.
Barakamon
Dacchi Ikode
Translation:
Let's All Go
Together
Darn that Kawafuji!
Doesn't he even care to listen to me?
I was talking big to Kawafuji,
Naruka Competition Entry
"Star"
Artist: Handa Seishuu
Name: Handa Sei
Address, Phone:
Kawafuji House of the Arts
but is this really the one I should submit?
I think it's good calligraphy,
but on the whole, it feels like
it was done on a whim.
Can I really call this calligraphy mine?
If it's calligraphy I could only
write because I came to the island,
I don't know for sure if I could
write the same way in Tokyo.
Crap... now I'm worried.
Even though it's an exhibition
that won't reject my work,
should I really submit a piece I wrote on a whim?
Think positive, positive!
It won't do any good to brood over it now.
Right now, my only weapon
is the inspiration of nature.
If I anguish over whether it's "my"
calligraphy, the deadline will...
Naru, what do you think?
Huh? 'Bout what?
Let's talk about what to play instead!
"Instead"?
I'm not playing with you.
I'm a proud guy, and I'm asking for your opinion.
Ya sure ya wanna say that?
Flash.
Ticket to do anything you say.
One time.
Shoot!
I should've given her a ticket for
a shoulder massage instead.
So long as I have this, ya hafta do what I say!
No, I wrote "one time" on it.
Grampa!
Naru!
What are they doing?
We're pilin' up stones to make a wall.
It's a typhoon barrier.
Ya gotta fit the stones together
just right, or it'll fall apart.
So it's like a puzzle!
Okay, try placin' a stone.
Is he trying to casually talk me into helping?!
Sensei's huntin' for toads with me!
I'm usin' this!
Toads?!
Ticket to do anything you say.
One time.
In that case...
I'll use this to get him to help me all day.
Sure, that I can do.
Hey, that was mine!
I'll give ya somethin' nicer, Naru.
Somethin' nicer?!
What d'ya mean?!
Here.
What's this?
It's a perfect skippin' stone!
Isn't that nice, Naru?
Forget it!
Good one...
C'mon and help, Sensei.
It's... heavy...
Take 'er over there.
Tch!
Let's see, I'll set this...
Like so...
It's a real thrill when it fits perfectly.
Yeah, ain't it?
Yer real good at this.
I just may be suited for this kind of precise task.
The ones we piled up look a right mess,
an' I thought we'd done good.
Yer real bad at this, Grampa!
And yer too honest!
While we're at it, how 'bout we have
Sensei handle that thing at the shrine?
Oh, right, that.
What thing?
C'mon in.
Pardon the intrusion.
What am I supposed to do here at the shrine?
Purification?
Here, look at this.
These're the names of ev'ryone who
donated when the shrine was built.
It's pretty much all the villagers from back then.
I was thinkin' it was 'bout time we got it rewritten.
Here, take this.
It's the village register.
I'd thought of askin' someone
in town to handle the job,
but you'd do it better, right?
Take this.
Wow, this is amazing.
It's an antique.
It won't be much,
but we'll give ya a little somethin' as thanks.
I don't need any money.
Ain't up for it?
It's not that.
I was just thinking that it's been a while
since I wrote such orderly calligraphy.
Write some good calligraphy again.
There's room for one more name here.
So that people know who wrote it,
how 'bout you add yer name, Sensei?
Should I?
I didn't donate anything.
Shh!
That'll be just between us.
Then I shouldn't...
Sensei!
There's a phone call for you at the store.
It's from Kawafuji-san.
That guy, after ignoring me earlier...
Here, take these to the house.
Sure.
Why'd Kawafuji call?
He said it was an important discussion.
What's an important discussion?
Grown-up talk.
What's wrong, Naru?
My ticket to make him do anythin' I say...
I hadn't asked him anythin' yet,
but then Grampa used it!
That's too bad.
What were you planning to ask him to do?
Lessee...
I wanna go with Sensei to the festival,
and to the beach again,
and to the sports meet, too!
Oh, and hiking, too.
And then...
For things like that,
I think he'd agree even if you didn't use a ticket.
Oh, yeah!
That'll be fun!
In that case, let's plan on goin' to the festival!
I wanna wear a kimono!
Okay, let's invite Miwa-nee and Tama, too!
It'll be a pain with those two around.
Yer goin' too, right, Akki?
Yeah!
Yeah.
I see.
Yeah, got it.
I'll come home.
All right!
Learning From The Past
I'm going with this one!
I'll use this!
Indeed.
You've done well to endure my
long training and come this far.
I have nothing left to teach you.
You both are certain to get gold prizes!
Yeah!
I tried to sound enthusiastic,
but will I really be okay?
After I wrote it with so much fighting spirit,
what if I don't get any prize at all?
Now I don't want to turn it in.
You dummies!
I taught you!
Your calligraphy is as good as anyone's!
Ya really think so, Sensei?
In fact, I'm more worried about myself.
I don't really know if the work
I chose to exhibit is good or not...
Sensei!
Sensei, take us to the festival!
You promised!
There, all set.
You actually know how to dress
someone in a yukata? I'm impressed.
It's so cute!
This stuff is easy.
I could even dress you in a real kimono.
Wow...
You're coming to the festival too, right?
Yeah.
C'mon! Let's get goin'!
Festival, festival!
Okay, we're goin' too, so see ya there!
Thanks for the lessons!
Sure.
C'mon, Sensei!
Hurry up!
All right, already!
A festival, huh...
I guess I'll go for a change of pace.
Ya look happy, Sensei.
I-I'm not happy about this or anything!
Hey!
Festival!
Well, why not?
After all, it's my last day here.
Gotou Bus Business Office
Yay! Festival, festival!
Heya! What'll ya have?
Tonme Festival
Sensei! This way!
So this is a festival...
I hardly ever went to any while I was in Tokyo.
Grade School
Sei-san, let's go to the festival!
No. He has a calligraphy exhibition.
High School
Handa, let's go to the festival!
Sei-san has a calligraphy exhibition. Sorry.
University
Handa-kyun, let's go to the festival!
Handa has a calligraphy exhibition.
I'll go instead.
It hurts to remember.
Especially since it's right before another exhibition...
Sensei!
Hot Dogs
Goldfish Scooping
Sensei! Goldfish! Goldfish!
That's the "Goldfish Scooping" I've heard about!
Oho, yer here, Sensei!
Crayfish      Goldfish
It's the gangst— er, I mean, Miwa's dad.
I'm helpin' out the commerce
and industry association.
Huh, sounds like a lot of work.
Okay, one hundred yen!
Seriously?
Can you really scoop with this?
Do yer best, Sensei!
Yeah!
Now!
Huh?
Yer bad at this, Sensei.
Sir, isn't this scoop defective?!
That ain't so. Yer just bad.
! One more time...
Sensei, could you move aside for a moment?
Oh, you're the nurse.
It's Iku-nee!
For this, you can't make a big splash.
Just watch Iku-chan's slick moves.
I-It's...
as if the goldfish are asking to be scooped!
Goldfish Scooping
Oh! It's Iku!
She's amazin' as always.
Iku-chan comin' by puts me in the red.
Though there ain't no way
she needs this many fish...
True...
Now for the last spurt!
Iku!
What're you doin', Aiko?!
Iku-chan, this's no good.
Ah! I was 'bout to set a new record!
Ikuko lays waste to the goldfish
scoopin' every single year.
The teacher!
"Ev'rything in moderation,"
I always taught her at the branch school.
Huh, you don't say...
I think he wants me to point out something,
but I'll ignore him...
You couldn't catch any goldfish.
It's a lot of work taking care of a pet,
so I decided not to catch any.
Somethin's goin' on there!
What could it be?
It's a free-throw competition.
It's Akki!
Akki!
Teams of four can win festival tickets
based on the number of points they make.
We're playing, too!
The brats!
We're on the same team.
If not for the middle schoolers
blinded by their greed for tickets,
we would be certain to take first place.
First place is 5,000 yen!
Let's show 'em that the
softball team is invincible!
Okay, Miwacchi!
The air around them is dead...
Hey, isn't Tama with you?
Oh, Sensei!
Tama went to buy a manga that came out today.
We hafta have four people to do this,
so I wish she'd get back soon!
It's the Sensei we've heard about!
Wow, what a hottie!
Nice shot, Akki!
That Akki's awful brazen for a sixth grader.
Akki's got pretty high specs,
despite his appearance.
We're up next! What's Tama doin'?!
She's late!
Meanwhile, Tama is...
Why isn't it here on the release date?!
Ain't it always like this?
Next, the Softball Glasses Team!
This's bad, Miwacchi!
Please come forward.
Ah! That rotten glasses girl!
Sensei, help us!
You just hafta get one shot in!
Just get one in? It's not that easy!
Okay, first shot!
There!
Second shot!
Third shot!
You guys are too good at this!
Aren't you on the softball team?!
It's 'cuz we help out with the
basketball team sometimes.
There ain't many people,
so there's plenty of give and take.
Rural clubs are incredibly flexible...
Here!
C'mon, get goin', Sensei!
Huh? For real?!
Do I have to do this?
Do yer best, Sensei!
I never thought this day would come,
when I would reveal my hidden talent.
Yes, long ago, I...
read a basketball manga!
The winner is the Akki Squad!
They did well for grade schoolers!
Very impressive!
Sensei, cheer up.
No...
I thought I could do it...
Here, Sensei!
It ain't much, but second place got us tickets,
so here's your share: 300 yen.
Can I really have this, even though I missed?
It's Tama's share, but since she ain't here...
Meanwhile, Tama is...
I asked you to reserve me a copy!
Why'd you sell it?!
We'll get another one soon.
What the heck?!
Takoyaki
Yakisoba
Cotton Candy
Drinks
What do you want to eat?
I'll buy you anything you like.
Yay!
I'll have takoyaki!
Yakisoba!
You're getting cotton candy.
Cheapskate!
Ya just said you'll buy anything!
Don't assume all grown-ups have money!
Forget it, I'll buy my own.
Me, too.
You kids have money?!
And you're flaunting it!
If ya want somethin', say so!
I'll buy it for ya!
Stop it!
I can't have a seven-year-old
child spending money on me!
Just let her treat you.
Hiro!
Why don't you get the yakisoba?
It'll go towards the baseball club.
I do have some money...
But I'll just use these tickets
to get three cotton candy.
He really is a cheapskate...
Here's a nice big one.
All right!
Here.
Yay!
Here you go, Sensei.
Thank you!
Thanks, Sensei!
So this is cotton candy...
Where do I start eating it from?
Here? Here?
Here? No, maybe here?
Will Sensei be all right in that crowd?
I hope he doesn't get cotton candy on anyone's
clothes, or hurt himself with the chopsticks...
Hiroshi, I got more yakisoba!
Tonme Festival
Festival
The drum's real loud!
Real loud!
The fireworks display will begin at nine o'clock.
She said there's fireworks, Sensei!
Yeah.
Be careful not to get lost, you two!
Oh!
Hey!
Sensei, this way!
Right after I said...
Naru!
Hina!
, it's dark.
Sensei...
Tama, what are you doing?
Reading the manga I bought.
Well, I don't like crowds,
so I spend every summer festival like this.
Not that I'm one to talk,
but you're wasting your youth.
Have you seen Naru and Hina—
That's too bright!
Since they took this road,
they went to the beach.
It's time for the fireworks,
so let's go together.
There's a good little-known spot.
Oh! Sensei came!
Tama, where'd ya go?
Oh, sorry. I was reading manga.
Huh? Where are the softball team girls?
They're watchin' the fireworks
with their boyfriends.
Oh? I wish they'd blow up.
Tama?!
Oh! Here's Naru and Hina!
So you came too, Hiro-nii.
No girlfriend?
If I had one, I wouldn't be cooking yakisoba.
Sorry. I know, but I asked anyway.
Well, we've got the usual crew here.
Yeah.
Summer break's almost over...
This year sure was fun.
After school starts, there'll
be a lot less time for fun.
Ya studyin' for exams, Hiro-nii?
No, job huntin'.
By "job," do you mean one on the island?
No, off.
Aww, that's sad!
Well, there's still some time.
Yer right.
And even without you here,
there'll still be Sensei.
Ya sayin' Sensei can take my place?!
Listen...
There's something I have to tell you.
It's started!
Eek! It's too bright!
Wow!
Amazin'!
Hey...
What was Sensei tryin' to say just now?
Who knows...
Take a good look at him.
Even without words,
Sensei's back speaks volumes.
Sensei! I came to play!
Huh?
Sensei!
Sensei?
Ain't nobody comin'...